Sargent, Charles Sprague, 1841-1927. Records of the Director Charles Sprague Sargent, 1893-1927 (inclusive): A Finding Aid.
Records of the Director Charles Sprague Sargent, 1893-1927 (inclusive).
- IV: Sargent Publications
  - Folder 4:
    - October 21, 1911. For Closer Relations Between Commercial Horticulture and Scientific Institutions. Horticulture p.559.
  - Folder 5:
    - November 1917. The Arnold Arboretum -- What It Is and What It Does. Garden Magazine pp. 122-125.
  - Folder 6:
    - March 15, 1917. A Garden of Trees. The Youth's Companion.
  - Folder 7:
    - 1918, 1919. Notes on North American Trees. Reprint from The Botanic Gazette.
  - Folder 8:
    - January 1922. The First Fifty Years of the Arnold Arboretum. Journal of the Arnold Arboretum 3(3):127-171.
  - Folder 9:
    - A Guide to the Arnold Arboretum. 2nd ed., Riverside Press, 1925.
  - Folder 10:
    - October 1925. The Caleb William Loring Estate at Prides Crossing, Mass. Horticulture p. 393.
  - Folder 11:
    - April 15, 1925. David Sears, Tree Planter. Horticulture pp.164-165.
  - Folder 12:
    - 1926. The Trees of Mount Vernon, Report. Revised ed.
  - Folder 13:
    - February 1927. The Greatest Garden in America, The Arnold Arboretum. Home Acres pp. 95, 112.
  - Folder 14:
    - 1909. "The Trees of Commonwealth Avenue Boston."
  - Folder 15:
    - January 3, 1886. Asa Gray. Sun.
  - Folder 16:
    - 1886. Trees and Tree Planting in Massachusetts. Annual Report of the Massachusetts State Forester.
  - Folder 17:
    - 1905. The Pinetum at Wellesley, Massachusetts. Extracted from The Life, Letters and Diary of Horatio Hollis Hunnewell.
  - Folder 18:
    - 1917. Botanical Activities of Percival Lowell. Rhodora pp. 22-24.
  - Folder 19:
    - 1897. Report of the Committee Appointed by the National Academy of Sciences upon the Inauguration of Forest Policy for the Forest Lands of the United States. Washington, GPO.
  - Folder 20:
    - "Notes from the Arnold Arboretum." Reprints from various numbers of the Bulletin issued by the Arboretum. International Garden Club.
  - Folder 21:
    - Report on Forest Trees of North America, Tenth Census of the United States Forestry, 1880-1883. Forestry Bulletin #s1-6, 8-21, 23-25. List of wood specimens, May 1881.
  - Folder 22:
    - 1889. "Journal of Andre Michaux. 1785-1796." With letter.
- V: Books
  - (Box 1:)
  - Plantae Wilsonianae, Vol. I, 1913.
  - (Box 2:)
  - Plantae Wilsonianae, Vol. II, 1916.
  - (Box 3:)
  - Plantae Wilsonianae, Vol. III, 1917.
  - (Box 4:)
  - Trees and Shrubs: Illustrations of New or Little Known Ligneous Plants, 1905-1913.
  - (Box 5:)
  - 1880. A Catalogue of the Forest Trees of North America, 1880.
  - 1925. A Guide to the Arnold Arboretum, 1925.
  - 1922. Manual of the Trees of North America (Exclusive of Mexico), 1922.
  - New or Little Known North American Trees, 1889-1902.
- VI: Sargent Photographs
  - (Box 1)
  - 186? Photograph by LeJeune, Paris. Charles Sprague Sargent portrait as a young man.
  - 1866. Charles Sprague Sargent with group.
  - 1880. Charles Sprague Sargent, C.E. Faxon in Dwight House.
  - 1880. Charles Sprague Sargent, G. Englemann, Francis Skinner.
  - 1901. Charles Sprague Sargent and H.H. Hunnewell at the Massachusetts Horticultural Society.
  - 1904. Photo by T.E. Marr. Charles Sargent at bench in herbarium.
  - 1904. Photo by T.E. Marr. Charles Sprague Sargent in library at Arnold Arboretum examining Quercus herbarium specimens.
  - 1904. Photo by J.H. McFarland. Charles Sprague Sargent in Arnold Arboretum grounds.
  - 1904? Photo by J.H. McFarland. Charles Sprague Sargent in office at Arboretum Administration building.
  - 1907. Photo by A.G. Eldredge. Charles Sprague Sargent on grounds.
  - 1915. Charles Sprague Sargent and E.H. Wilson.
  - 1916. Alfred Rehder, E.H. Wilson, Charles Sprague Sargent.
  - 1922. Photo by R.W. Curtis. Charles Sprague Sargent with Rhododendron Obtusum kaempferi.
  - 1922. Charles Sprague Sargent and C.L. Hutchinson at Lake Geneva WI.
  - 1922. Charles Sprague Sargent, C.L. Hutchinson, and J. Morton at Lisle, IL.
  - 1924. Photo by A.E. Christiansen. Charles Sprague Sargent in library at Arnold Arboretum.
  - 192? Charles Sprague Sargent holding botanical illustration.
  - 1926. Charles Sprague Sargent and H.H. Hunnewell at Wellesley.
  - 1927. Charles Sprague Sargent Memorial Service. Mrs. John A. Stewart, Jr. (President of the Garden Club of America), Mrs. Henry S. Hunnewell, and Mr. Edwin S. Webster.
  - Charcoal sketch by John Singer Sargent. Charles Sprague Sargent.
  - Charles Sprague Sargent in library.
  - A retrospective study of Prof. Charles Sprague Sargent
  - Charles Sprague Sargent in doorway with Wisteria.
  - Photographs of two bas-relief images of Charles Sprague Sargent.
    1. Hanging in the 3rd floor library corridor. 2. Hanging at Harvard University Herbaria.
  - Two photographs of an oil painting of Charles Sprague Sargent.
    Hanging on the 4th floor of the Herbarium Building in Administration.
  - Charles Sprague Sargent with a few Harvard classmates at Holm Lea before 60th anniversary. Henry M. Rogers, Rev. Luther G. Barnett, Charles S. Sargent, Edward M. Tuck, Dr. Arthur H. Nichols.
  - Charles Sprague Sargent and others.
  - Sargent Family: Charles Sprague Sargent, C.S. Sargent, Jr, and C.S. Sargent III.
  - Sargent Family: C.S. Sargent, Jr., C.S. Sargent III, grandchild.
  - Sargent Family: Charles Sprague Sargent. Alice, Henrietta, Mary Sargent, Molly, Charles Jr., Robeson.
  - Sargent Memorial Service.